♪The night wind shakes off
the withered leaves♪
♪I open the window and gaze at the moon♪
♪Haze spreads across the river,
lanterns drifting♪
♪I hear the memories rustling♪
♪Garden flowers shed petals one by one♪
♪Candlelight flickers,
swaying with melancholy♪
♪I sigh by the lamp over the long night♪
♪Past memories unfold scene by scene♪
♪It's all your face♪
♪Boldly trampling over my heart♪
♪Two measures of ink I take,
one for love miswritten♪
♪And another for youth passed♪
♪With endless sorrow,
I once traced your silhouette♪
♪Two measures of ink I take,
one for joy and sorrow♪
♪And another for parting and reunion♪
♪I write until splendor fades,
and I am no more♪
=Prelude of the White Snake=
=Episode 9=
Suzhen, we've been walking for an hour,
and we're still near Xu Xian's house.
You don't actually want
to leave, do you?
I can't just leave like this.
I can't swallow this.
Well, why bother
getting upset over a mortal?
A mortal's lifespan
is barely a hundred years.
Even if he can help you ascend,
you don't need to get attached to him.
Besides, Xu Xian is riddled with flaws.
He's rigid,
dull,
and stubborn.
The only decent thing
about him is his face.
But he's still far inferior
to those handsome men in the storybooks.
Most importantly, he is so ungrateful.
You've gone out of your way for him,
yet he doesn't appreciate it.
Though Miss Bai
is a bit ignorant
of the ways of the world,
she has always had
your best interests at heart.
I heard she went to the Zhao's shop
to buy me a birthday gift.
Think about it. Was that really for me?
Actually, it was all for you.
Why?
To make you look good.
Your uncle and I know
all about those birthday gifts
you give us every year.
I never gave any.
You just refuse to admit it.
Listen,
if you really don't want
Miss Bai to leave,
then go bring her back.
Believe it or not,
she's still near your house right now.
Why are you looking at me?
Go bring her back.
He's indeed dull
and rigid.
But I think
he's much better than those playboys
who frequent the brothels.
He looks quite decent.
It's true that he's ungrateful.
But after all,
this is a love trial,
so it's supposed
to be a bit of difficult.
Suzhen, why are you defending him now?
Don't tell me you're falling for him.
Absolutely not.
He's nothing but a mere mortal.
He doesn't deserve you.
How is this possible?
How could I ever fall for him?
I just want him to fall for me sooner,
so I can ascend faster.
Miss Bai.
Young Master Qing.
I knew you two are still here.
Aunt, why are you here?
I came to thank you
for your thoughtful gift.
Aunt, you know about it?
I heard you
arguing with Xu Xian just now.
Where are you going to stay tonight?
Xu Xian is a bit ignorant
of the ways of the world.
He is rigid, dull,
and stubborn.
A man like that needs
to be left to stew for a while.
Otherwise, he'll never cherish
those who around him.
Do you agree?
Come on, stay at my house.
Stay for several days
and let him stew for a bit.
Young Master Qing, you come along too.
My husband is a constable.
You can help me teach him a lesson.
No problem.
Let's go.
Fellow townsfolk!
Xu Xian, relying on his uncle Fang Qiru
being a constable,
indulged his lover, Bai Suzhen,
in committing assault.
Not only did she slap me in the face,
she also smashed
my family's jade carving.
And she refused to compensate.
My poor, elderly mother is over seventy,
and now she's bedridden.
Tell me, if Xu Xian doesn't
compensate me thousands of taels,
how can that be justified?
It can't be, right?
This Zhao brat usually bullies people,
and now he's playing the victim.
Don't let him latch onto you.
Aunt.
She told me to come
make birthday pastries with her.
Where is she?
Suzhen.
That Zhao brat came to cause trouble.
He's making a scene at the front gate.
Aunt has rushed over.
Perfect timing to vent.
Let's go.
Zhao Puxin,
your shouting
has scared off sparrows under my eaves.
What? Did you not learn your lesson?
Are you here for another round today?
Y-You... Lu Wenhui!
As the matriarch of Fang family,
how can you aid and abet evil?
That Bai Suzhen,
she hit me!
All the neighbors here know it.
Zhao Puxin.
What do you want?
How dare you come here
and twist the truth.
Don't blame me if I get rough.
Qing.
Hold on.
Such a trifle doesn't need
Young Master Qing to step in.
Just leave it to me.
Everyone,
since Zhao Puxin here
wants you all to uphold justice,
then I may trouble you for a while.
Miss Bai beside me
looks delicate and frail.
How could she possibly
injure Young Master Zhao severely?
Moreover, Young Master Zhao
claims his injuries are severe,
yet today he's making a big show
with voice as loud as thunder.
- True.
- Yeah.
Bai Suzhen, you tell them.
Did you hit me?
If no one harassed her first,
why would a young woman like her
try every mean to defend herself?
Zhao Puxin, do you admit it?
You saw Miss Bai,
coveted her,
and tried to harass her.
Exactly.
Zhao Puxin harassed a girl
on the street before.
Yeah, he's a repeat offender.
Shut up! All of you, shut up!
S-She indeed smashed my jade carving!
What a coincidence.
The pawnshop owner in the east part
of town admitted it himself
(Pawnshop receipt)
that your family heirloom
was pawned by you long ago
to fuel your gambling.
The one that got smashed
is a fake you bought last year
for a measly three qian.
Then her husband Fang Qiru must have
threatened the pawnshop owner.
As a constable, my husband
gets salary from the government
and has always been upright and honest.
You're slandering him.
Aren't you afraid
that you'd get doubly guilty?
After all, you've already
committed extortion
and harassment of a woman.
Hurry up!
What took you so long?
I'm telling you,
Lu Wenhui
is abusing her power to bully me.
Madam Zhao is already aware
of the full story.
She sent me to apologize.
We've prepared a birthday gift for you,
and someone will deliver it shortly.
Thank you.
Madam Zhao has prepared
another gift for you.
Please accept it.
You hit me?
What's wrong with you?
Madam Zhao told me to do so.
She also sent you a message.
You wretched son!
If you keep misbehaving like this,
I'll kick you out of the Zhao family.
Young Master Zhao, let's go home.
You!
Young Master Zhao, if you keep this up,
Madam Zhao might have another gift.
Make way!
Young Master Zhao!
- Let's go.
Miss Bai,
since you're staying at my house,
I'll shelter you.
Come with me to the kitchen.
Okay.
Aunt, you are amazing.
(Xu Xian's aunt)
(is now the only mortal I like.)
Uncle invited me for tea.
Why are you here?
I'm here to mooch a meal.
Your aunt and uncle are kind people,
so they won't mind.
You had a spat with Miss Bai,
so you should go make up.
Both of you refuse to back down.
What is this?
Besides,
Miss Bai went
to that Zhao's shop for you.
Aren't you a monk?
I'm just a disciple.
Does that mean
you can butt in on my business?
I don't want to.
But as a friend,
I can't just watch you be so blind.
- You clearly like...
- No, I don't.
I'm sure you know it best.
Uncle.
Captain Fang,
do you still remember me?
I'm Fahai from Jinshan Temple.
Fahai.
The most handsome head disciple
of Jinshan Temple.
You surely have a great memory.
Oh, my master asked me
to bring you this protective charm
to ward off evil and disasters.
Thank your master for me.
Let's wait out front.
Your aunt and the others
will be here soon.
Okay.
Xu Xian, why don't you go over?
You have to make the first move.
Aunt.
You're here too.
You followed us here
last night, didn't you?
Well, your aunt
made these pastries today.
You all must have a good taste today.
Let's have a taste.
Come on.
Aunt made them herself?
These pastries must taste perfect.
Fahai, take it easy, don't choke.
You eat too.
Delicious.
It's okay. You eat.
- Come on, one for each of you.
- Come on.
Here, one for you.
Is it good?
- Yes.
Delicious.
Fahai, take it easy, don't choke.
I'll make you more later.
Bring some back
for your fellow disciples.
Stop stuffing your face.
Aunt made them for Xu Xian.
Xu Xian, have some more.
You...
What did you say?
Aunt thinks about you all the time.
She made these pastries
especially for you.
You should have some more.
What? Do you think they're not good?
Xu Xian, you don't come home often.
Eat a few more.
Okay.
All of you, make sure you finish them.
Heard me?
Uncle, you should eat some too.
Oh, my brain.
I still have work to do
at the yamen.
I completely forgot.
I have to go back to the yamen now.
Alright, I'll see you off.
Okay.
You guys, finish them all.
♪I also gave my youth to someone♪
♪I must admit, you made the journey♪
♪When loving you
became instinct, what's left♪
♪Seals a fate too brutal to amend♪
♪Clumsy and new, we gave our first kiss♪
♪Never thought passionate eyes
would turn cold♪
♪I thought of pulling away,
but I'd barely begun♪
♪Having loved you so deep,
how could I love another♪
♪Even if we're strangers again,
why deny we loved♪
♪Though I'm stubborn,
I never stopped you from loving others♪
♪I shouldn't have been so foolish
to think there was still hope♪
♪But you won't even admit what we had♪
♪Even if we're strangers again,
why deny we loved♪
♪Though I have questions,
I never questioned you♪
♪I'll lock you away and set myself free♪
♪After all, I'm the one you deny♪
♪Having ever loved♪